TAYYABA IFZAL

MBPsS

TAYYABA.AFZAL@GMAIL.COM 07432362487

PROFILE

I am a psychology graduate and currently a part-time postgraduate student at Newman University. My educational and work experience has diversified my horizon as well as prepared me for future challenges. I am an ambitious, enthusiastic, and optimistic person with great problem-solving skills. I am very adaptive to situations, be it working in a team or alone. My communication, organisation, and interpersonal skills have always been praised at my workplace.

EDUCATION

BSc Psychology (First-Class Honours)

Foundation University Islamabad, Pakistan

- Graduated with CGPA 3.63 / 4.0 90% Equiv.UK Grade 1st
- (Qualification certified with UK NARIC & BPS Membership No. 543965)

Modules included:

• Clinical Assessment, Child Psychology, Gender psychology, Educational psychology, Statistics, Research methods, Health psychology, Mental health and psychopathology, Cognitive psychology

Distinguished Achievements

Participated in and organised:

- Mental health day conference on "Young People and Mental Health in A Changing World"
- 1st International conference on "Emerging Trends in Psychology; Preparing for 21st Century"
- "Psychotherapeutic Camp" in Foundation University Rawalpindi Campus
- Workshop on "Adolescence Issues in Females" at The Yasin School
- Workshop on "Bullying and Effects of Bullying on Teenagers"
- Awareness session on "Promoting Hygiene and Moral Values Among Slum Children"

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022 - Present:

Customer Service Advisor NHSBT at Teleperformance:

I work as a customer service advisor and my role includes answering general enquiries and specific queries for donors, booking them in for their blood donation session, advising them regarding health and travel guidelines as well as sending their referrals when needed.

2021 – 2022:

Academic Marking Assistant (AMA) at Coventry University:

My role includes marking and grading coursework for psychology students and making sure that the course requirements are fulfilled. My job requires working with different professors and students which has polished my communication skills.

2016 - 2020:

• Internship at Armed Force Institute of Mental Health (AFIMH Rawalpindi)

My role was at AFIMH was as an assistant counsellor and assistant psychometrician. Assessment of new recruits and dealing with patients with mental illness was part of the internship. Revising DSM-V and all psychometric tools was also done during the internship.

• Internship at Benazir Hospital, Rawalpindi

My role in this internship was as an assistant psychologist. Making case reports, performing initial assessments, and taking the history of clients was learned and practised during this internship.

• Internship at Child Protection and Welfare Bureau, Rawalpindi.

During this internship, I worked as an assistant psychologist. This institute was mainly focused on homeless, destitute, neglected and abused children. My role included counselling children and motivating them about getting education and skills so they can have a better life for themselves and their families. Taking the initial mental examination and history of children was also part of my job.

SKILLS

- · Leadership Skills
- Teamwork
- Communication
- Project Management
- · Organisational skills
- Problem-solving
- Willingness to learn
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Microsoft Excel
- SPSS
- Fluency in English & Urdu